Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin slavery collection, 1728-1973.
Rudin (Gail and Stephen) Slavery Collection,
- Series VI: Letters
  - Regarding circulars that were distributed advertising a phony emigration plan for freedmen to go to Peru, October 6 and 19, 1866; Writer: William Seward Writer's location: Washington, DC Addressee: JL Barreda Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 687
  - Complaint written on behalf of slave, asking to get her child back, August 17, 1867; Location: Georgia Format: ALS (Box 16, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 35
  - Freed slave writes his former mistress inquiring about his age., January 3, 1871; Writer: Henry Lowry Writer's location: New Garden, North Carolina Addressee: Betsy Lowry Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 574
  - Garrison writes to Briggs reviewing the letter he had written to warn black voters that Sumber is a poor advisor and not to accept his conclusions, August 20, 1872; Writer: William Lloyd Garrison Writer's location: Roxbury, Massachussetts Addressee: Reverend WT Briggs Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 975
  - Sumner writes "much has been done, but more remains to be done", April 16, 1873; Writer: Charles Sumner Writer's location: Washington, DC Addressee: Edward M. Turner Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 775
  - Pratt requests Singer Sewing Machine for Colored School. Accompanied by a Cover Letter Encouraging the Donation, June 12, July 11, 1873; Writer: Enoch Pratt Writer's location: Baltimore, Maryland Addressee: Singer Manufacturing Co. Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 453
  - Seeks to Open a Fully-Integrated College for the Poor, May 15-17, 1881; Location: Elk Falls, Kansas Format: ALS (Box 16, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 418
  - Lewis George Clark Letter, regarding Uncle Tom's Cabin, February 18, 1892; Writer: Lewis George Clark Addressee: Mr. Roland Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 26)
    Rudin # S - 190
  - Letter in which Douglass downplays the contributions of famous African Americans, especially women, August 26, 1892; Writer: Frederick Douglass Writer's location: Cedar Mill, Ancostia, DC Addressee: Dr. Monroe Alpheus Majors Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 1017
  - Harriet Beecher Stowe Letter, regarding Uncle Tom's Cabin, March 27, 1893; Writer: Harriet Beecher Stowe Addressee: Mr. Robb Format: ALS (Box 4, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 189
- Series VII: Manumissions
  - William Collins Frees Three of his Slaves at Future Dates, January 13, 1781; Location: Kent County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 399
  - Revolutionary War Slave Manumission, September 5, 1782 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 83
  - Manumission Document - Mary London, Female Slave, August 11, 1788; Location: Ann Arundel County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 260
  - Manumission Document - woman and child, June 22, 1795; Location: Ann Arundel County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 261
  - Manumission Document - Thomas Freed at the Expiration of Four Years, April 13, 1796; Location: Ann Arundel County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 263
  - "Recognizance" document freeing a woman and fining the man who brought her into Delware against the law, February 21, 1799; Location: Ann Arundel County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 262
  - Peter to be freed 1806, Harry 1809, Poll 1812, and Ned in 1819, June 12, 1801; Location: Ann Arundel County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Certificate of freedom for John Jones, December 23, 1807; Location: Frederick County Court Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 904
  - Manumission of Female Slaves, 1812 and 1814; Location: New York (Box 16, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 13
  - A Manumission of "A Coloured Man, Mariner", October 26, 1822; Location: New York City Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 16, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 490
  - Certificate of Freedom for George Howard, November 7, 1828; Location: Alleghany County, Pennsylvania Format: Vellum Doc (Box 41, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 223
  - Slave Pays for her Certificate of Freedom - Included is a Receipt for a Payment, August 24, 1830; Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 276
  - Manumission for a slave and her four children, March 27, 1832; Location: San Felipe de Austin Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 669
  - Slave Emancipation and Freedom Bond, March 7, 1837; Location: Sangamon County, Illinois Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 36)
    Rudin # S - 277
  - Son Makes oath Verifying Manumission of a Slave who was Manumitted 21 Years Before by his Father, June 18, 1827; Location: Frederick County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 594
  - Document certifying that woman is a freed slave and that her daughter was born free, February 15, 1839; Location: County of Rockingham Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 36)
    Rudin # S - 288
  - Manumission Document, Henry Skinner, March 11, 1840; Location: Frederick County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 37)
    Rudin # S - 23
  - Deed of freedom for 14 year old Henry Blake, August 19, 1842; Location: Philadelphia, Pennsylvania Format: Ptd Doc (Box 40, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 1026
  - Rhode Island Freedom Papers, October 29, 1842; Location: Rhode Island Format: Ptd DocS (Box 16, Folder 37)
    Rudin # S - 316
  - Certificate of manumission for a woman and her son by Charles Hempstead, April 21, 1845; Location: Galena, Illinois Format: MDocs (Box 40, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 768
  - Freedom Bond for a Slave, 1853; Location: Kentucky (Box 16, Folder 38)
    Rudin # S - 168
  - Official Freedom Certificate for Woman Polly Bundy, February 28, 1853; Location: Virginia Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 38)
    Rudin # S - 541
  - Partly-Printed Proof of Slave Manumission, May 17, 1856; Location: Baltimore County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 18, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 274
  - Slave manumission signed by Matilda with an "X". She promises to leave Kentucky within 90 days, March 12, 1861; Location: Commonwealth of Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 776
  - Document Manumitting London Henry and his Family, August 22, 1862; Location: Port Royal, South Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 39)
    Rudin # S - 425
  - Enlisted slave gains manumission, 3 documents, 1863; Location: Maryland (Box 40, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 78
  - Slave Emancipation with Proviso that Slave will Leave the State within 90 days, September 7, 1863; Location: Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 40, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 221
- Series VIII: Maps
  - Map of Southern Africa by Bradford, 1838 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Rudin Map #2
  - Map of Liberia, 1845; Location: Format: (Box 4, Folder 40)
    Rudin # S - 942
  - Map of Africa by L. Antoine, Paros, 1855 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Rudin Map #1
- Series IX: Miscellaneous Documents
  - Alex Haley draft pages, Undated; Format: Typed manuscript (Box 4, Folder 42a)
    Two typed pages from early draft of "Roots" with extensive editing and corrections by Alex Haley- (A portion of Chapter 84 where Kizzy is raped.) With color photo.
    Rudin # S - 303
  - New York Draft Riots broadside, "DON'T unchain the tiger!", Format: Broadside (Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 1047
  - Colonial Slave Document regarding abuse on slave, June 20, 1728; Location: England (Box 16, Folder 39)
    Rudin # S - 68
  - Bill of Lading for Seven Boys and One Girl, August 7, 1732; Location: Barbados to Boston, Massachusetts Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 4, Folder 41)
    Rudin # S - 265
  - Bill of Lading for a Slave Girl, August 7, 1732; Location: Barbados to Boston, Massachusetts Format: Ptd Doc (Box 16, Folder 40)
    Rudin # S - 264
  - Constable's Bill for Services Provided in the Execution of Two Slaves Charged with Poisoning, January 10, 1752; Location: Ashley Ferry Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 42)
    Rudin # S - 300
  - Contract Between William Harrison, John Finn and Sam Dennis Involving 1690 Pounds, April 12, 1761; Format: MDocS (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 457
  - Manuscript letter to William Pinnegar giving witness to the Atlantic slave triangle trade, July 17, 1764; Location: Newport, Rhode Island Signed: Aaron Lopez (Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 785
  - Colonial document recording sale of land by a free African American, March 25, 1768; Location: Brintwood, New Hampshire Format: Ptd Docs (Box 16, Folder 42)
    Rudin # S - 746
  - Invoice cargo of the ship active that would be exchanged for slaves in a triangle trade, August 11, 1768; Location: Newport Format: MDoc (Box 16, Folder 41)
    Rudin # S - 732
  - Instructions to the Captain of a Captured Vessel Carrying Slaves, March 7, 1778; Location: On Board the Marlborough at Montserrado Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 43)
    Rudin # S - 352
  - Smuggling African Cloth to America from St. Eustatius, December 22, 1779; Location: St. Eustatius Format: Ptd MDocS (Box 4, Folder 43)
    Rudin # S - 463
  - Pair of receipts signed by black Connecticut soldiers in the Revolution for rations and pay, June 21, 1780 and June 1, 1782; Location: Connecticut Format: MDocS, Ptd Docs (Box 4, Folder 44)
    Rudin # S - 673
  - Complying with the Abolition of Slavery Act in Pennsylvania, October 10, 1780; Location: Allentown, PA Format: MDocS (Box 4, Folder 45)
    Rudin # S - 242
  - Document granting permission to ship "four Negroes" to New York, December 6, 1782; Location: South Carolina (Box 4, Folder 46)
    Rudin # S - 71
  - Juba Freeman, a black Revolutionary War soldier receives pay signed by master Richard Law, December 27, 1784; Location: Hartford Format: Ptd Docs (Box 4, Folder 47)
    Rudin # S - 692
  - Slave Ship Brigantine Washington Muster Roll, 1787; Location: Newport, RI; Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 586
  - County Sheriff's announcement of slave to be claimed, March 1, 1790; Location:Pasquotank County, North Carolina Format: ALS (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 729
  - Letter to Georgia Gov. Edward Telfair, concerning death sentence of a slave, April 25, 1792 (Box 16, Folder 44)
    Rudin # S - 80
  - Insurance Policy for Slave Ship Hibernia, October 10, 1797; Location: Rhode Island (Box 16, Folder 45)
    Rudin # S - 115
  - Oath of Allegiance of a Schoolmaster, July 5, 1799; Location: Harington, New Jersey Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 398
  - Quakers Procure Title for Land on Which The Meeting House and Graveyard are Situated, 1802; Format: DOC (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S-376
  - Warrant for Seizure of Slave Ship Washington, 1801; Location: Rhode Island (Box 16, Folder 46)
    Rudin # S - 149
  - New York Slave Birth Certificate, March 15, 1805; Location: New York Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 214
  - Certification of Brown Seaman's American Citizenship, October 30, 1812; Location: District of Baltimore Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 409
  - Archive of the slave revolt aboard the Brig Agent, January 20, 1811; Location: Charleston, South Carolina (Box 16, Folder 47)
    Rudin # S - 647
  - Deposition of two British officers regarding the capture of 233 African Slaves, July 11, 1813; Location: Sierra Leone Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 48)
    Rudin # S - 635
  - Government Reimbursement Document for Servant's Clothing and Rations - War of 1812, November 9, 1814; Location: 1st New Hampshire Detached Militia Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 49)
    Rudin # S - 407
  - Slave is accused of murdering his master, ca. 1815; Location: Frederick County, Maryland Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 718
  - Andrew Jackson Invoice for Medical Care of his Slaves, Including Three Newborn Deliveries, July 24, 1818; Location: Melton's Bluff, Alabama Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 427
  - Massachusetts: Pauper Laws, 1820-1829; Location: Massachusetts Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 377
  - Census documents with "free white males", "Slaves", and "free colored persons", 1821; Location: Connecticut, Massachusetts, Rhode Island, Vermont Format: Ptd Doc (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 950
  - Census documents, 1821; Location: New Hampshire, New York Format: Ptd Doc (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 905
  - Medical assistance to be provided by Dr. Eli Ayers to U.S. agents and persons of colour delivered to Africa by U.S. vessels engaged in suppression of slave trade, July 21, 1821; Location: Navy Department Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 217
  - Mississippi Orders Man to Answer for Inflicting Cruel and Unusual Punishment on a Slave Woman, August 31, 1821; Location: Adams County, Mississippi Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 404
  - Kentucky Slave Oath, January 8, 1824; Location: Clay County, Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 251
  - Contract with Supervisor of Slave Gold Mine, September 19, 1831; Location: Burke County, North Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 16, Folder 50)
    Rudin # S - 206
  - Three Manuscript Documents Follow the Tribulations of Seven Slaves Trying to Attain Freedom, 1831-1832; Location: South Carolina and Illinois Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 597
  - Payment for Mid-Wife to Negro Woman, November 28, 1831; Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 350
  - Pennsylvania Illegitimacy Prosecution, November, 1834; Location: Adams County, Pennsylvania Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Rudin # S - 421
  - Two slaves testify they were hired by another slave to commit murder, June 2, 1837; Location: Ray County, Missouri Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 772
  - Lengthy Physician's Bill for Services Rendered to Slaves, 1838; Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 405
  - Sale of a Tobacco Crop for $150.75, August 10, 1838 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Rudin # S - 376
  - Letter Discusses Favorable Opportunities to Invest in Land and Slaves, September 5, 1839; Location: Plantation, Iberville; Format: ALS (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - List of 34 slaves, their names, ages and comments on their "character"; also includes a rating sheet on each slave's performance., ca. 1840-1860; Location: Constana (?) Plantation Format: MDS (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Rudin # S - 304
  - Physician's bill for over 100 visits to Thomas Kennedy's slaves, 1840s; Location: Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Rudin # S - 649
  - Proving Free Born Document, October 15, 1840; Location: Maryland (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Rudin # S - 22
  - Funding the Colonization Society, October 30, 1840; Location: Washington City Format: ALS (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Rudin # S - 314
  - Contract Agreeing to Guard and Accompany Mayse and his 20 Slaves Between Two Towns in Texas. Payment to be "a certain boy Reuben or $400", June 9, 1841; Location: County of Jefferson, Republic of Texas Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Rudin # S - 562
  - About the Brig "Sophia", Converted to a Slaver by her Officers on the Coast of Africa with a New Crew, False Papers and Flag, and a Cargo of Slaves, November 11, 1841; Location: Rio de Janiero Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 452
  - Whittier on the Abolitionist Crusade, with News of "another Amistad Affair", December 29, 1841; Format: ALS (Box 19, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 375
  - Dentist's Bills for Extracting Teeth From Slaves, April 8, 1843-September 22, 1843; Location: Alabama Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Rudin # S - 280
  - Slave Code Extracts, 1845; Location: Salem, Ohio (Box 13, Folder 38)
    Rudin # S - 181
  - Virginia Slave Pass, June 13, 1845 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Rudin # S - 39
  - Invoice for Medical Care Provided to his Slaves, January 22, 1846; Location: Wilcox County, Alabama Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Rudin # S - 512
  - Physician's Bill for Services Rendered to a Slave, January 1847; Location: Alabama Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Rudin # S - 278
  - Court Summons, re: gaming, fighting slaves, August 25, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Rudin # S - 191
  - Texas Plantation Slave Birth and Death Records, 1848-1862; Location: Texas Format: MDocS, Booklet (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Rudin # S - 521
  - Manifest of slave oath that the slave involved was not imported into the US, January 15, 1849; Format: Ptd Docs (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Four official letters regarding the U.S. involvement in the suppression of the illegal slave trade occurring on American ships., 1849 and 1850; Location: Brazil Format: LS (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 523
  - Children's Anti-Salvery missionary society certificate, ca. 1950; Location: Jocelyn, New York Format: Ptd Doc (Box 5, Folder 27)
    Rudin # S - 957
  - Overseer on the Beeches Plantation is Paid, January 1, 1850; Location: Beeches Plantation Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Rudin # S - 495
  - Document regarding a female slave charged with arson, July 22, 1850; Location: Georgia (Box 5, Folder 29)
    Rudin # S - 109
  - Slave Census Broadside, August 23, 1850; Location: County of Decatur, Georgia Format: Ptd BROADSIDE (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 318
  - Ordinance regarding number of lashes given to slaves, ca. 1850-1858; Location:Liberty, Missouri (Box 5, Folder 30)
    Rudin # S - 18
  - Sharecropper Contract, January 2, 1852; Location: Anderson County, Texas Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 31)
    Rudin # S - 283
  - African American Insurance Policy, Mutual Benefit Life and Fire Insurance Co., January 22, 1852; Location: Louisiana (Box 5, Folder 32)
    Rudin # S - 76
  - American Colonization Society Certificate (Signed by Henry Clay), June 22, 1852 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    Rudin # S - 57
  - Slave Patrols to Enforce Curfews, May 18, 1855; Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 34)
    Rudin # S - 235
  - Lottery Broadside with slaves as prizes, 1855; Location: Cincinnati, Ohio Format: Broadside (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 40
  - "Uncle Tom's Cabin" Theatre Broadside, March 31, 1857; Location: Worcester, Massachusetts Format: Ptd BROADSIDE (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 257
  - Florida Indictment for selling liquor to slaves, January 23, 1858 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    Rudin # S - 9
  - Banks Introduces Abolitionist Myrtilla Miner and Recommends Her Cause for Financial Aid, Seconded in a Note by James Thompson, March 16, October 13, 1858; Location: Salem and Boston, Massachusetts Format: ANS (Box 5, Folder 36)
    Rudin # S - 401
  - A petition requesting the state of Vermont to prohibit the surrender of fugitive slaves, November 13, 1858; Location: Vermont Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 37)
    Rudin # S - 856
  - Framed abolitionist broadside printed after John Brown's execution. "John Brown Still Lives", 1859; Location: Morrison, Illinois Format: Broadside (Box 38)
    Rudin # S - 844
  - Letterhead invoice of J. Tanenbaum and Co., 1859; Format: MDS (Box 5, Folder 37A)
    Rudin # S - 1043C
  - Slave Ship "Florida" Manifest, 1860; Location: Louisiana (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 89
  - "The Midnight Alarm (A True Story) - Story of a pregnant slave who accidentally gets shot by Union soldiers as she attempts to cross Union lines into freedom, ca. 1860s; Format: MS Story (Box 5, Folder 38)
    Rudin # S - 921
  - African American Rail Road Ticket, ca. 1860; Location: Alexandria to Vicksburg via Memphis Format: Ptd Ticket (Box 5, Folder 39)
    Rudin # S - 356
  - Quotation Declaring the Critical Importance of Abolishing Slavery, February 8, 1860; Location: Washington, DC Format: AQS (Box 5, Folder 40)
    Rudin # S - 445
  - Nine Items Pertaining to a Yankee Teacher in the South, December 1860- February 1865; Location: Louisiana Format: ALS (Box 5, Folder 41)
    Rudin # S - 346
  - Division of Slaves into Four Equal Lots - Estate of John Johnson, Deceased, January 3, 1861; Location: Madison County, Alabama Format: MDocS (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 461
  - Efforts of Underground Railroad, June 1861; Location: Uniontown, Kentucky Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 42)
    Rudin # S - 247
  - Cotton is shipped from Louisiana to England, June 8, 1861; Location: New Orleans, Louisiana Format: MDoc (Box 5, Folder 43)
    Rudin # S - 705
  - Slave Overseer's Journal Sheet - Daily Record of Hardscrabble Plantation, September 8-15, 1861; Location: Near Simmesport, Louisiana Format: MDOC (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Rudin # S - 319
  - Fourteen-day confederate pass for a free black member of North Carolina Infantry, February 14, 1862; Location: Camp Daniel, North Carolina Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 44)
    Rudin # S - 608
  - CSS Southern Republic Way Bill for 127 African Americans Passage, March 31, 1862; Location: North Carolina (Box 5, Folder 45)
    Rudin # S - 184
  - "Confiscation of Property and Emancipation of the Slaves of Rebels", speech of Hon. Albert Ely of New York, May 26, 1862; Format: Pamphlet (Box 5, Folder 45A)
    Rudin # S - 1044
  - Provision Return for Seven Black Teamsters, July 7-10, 1862; Location: Camp near Drewry's Bluff Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 46)
    Rudin # S - 431
  - Two Slave Patrol Related Items Signed by J.N. Whitner, one of the signers of the South Carolina Secession Ordinance, July 27, 1862; Location: Anderson, South Carolina Format: PASS and ALS (Box 5, Folder 47)
    Rudin # S - 323
  - A coffin and case receipt for a slave, with an etching of a funeral, July 28, 1862; Format: MDocS (Box 5, Folder 48)
    Rudin # S - 663
  - Order expelling all slaves not regularly hired from military camps, August 27, 1862; Location: Sedalia, Missouri Format: MDocS (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Rudin # S - 820
  - Soldier Interviews Slaves in Maryland - Slaves want to be Free, November 2-9, 1862; Location: Camp Chesapeake, Rockwell, Maryland Format: ALS (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 232
  - Confederate Slave Patrol Orders, December 15, 1862; Location: Dinwiddie County, Virginia Format: MDocS (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Rudin # S - 497
  - The Draft Riots in New York. The Metropolitan Police: Their Service During Riot Week., 1863; Author: David Barnes (Box 6, Folder 3A)
    Rudin # S - 1038
  - Confederate Imprint. Public Laws of the State of North Carolina, re: Slaves, Negro traders, 1863 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    Rudin # S - 58
  - Two Confederate bills: an act to provide payment to slave owners for slaves impressed under state laws, a bill to provide for raising two hundred thousand negro troops, 1863-1865; Location: Richmond, Virginia Format: Ptd Docs (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Rudin # S - 782
  - Contrabands On Board the Canal Boat "Kate", January 6, 1863; Location: Commissary Wharf Format: ALS (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Rudin # S - 307
  - Marriage license for "Thomas Tank, a Free Boy of Color" and Sallie Ann Lock, January 27, 1863; Location: Lawrence, Alabama Format: Ptd DocS (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Rudin # S - 761
  - Series D Bond- Liberty leaning on bales of Cotton, January 29, 1863; Format: Bond (Box 22, Folder 2)
    Rudin # S - 695
  - Transportation of slave for defenses, February 4, 1863; Location: Alabama (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Rudin # S - 64
  - Free woman enters volunteer slavery, March 1863; Location: Arkansas (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 119
  - Confederate Slave Impressment Form, May 9, 1863; Location: Abeeville, Henry County, Alabama Format: Ptd DOCS (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Rudin # S - 228
  - Special Orders No. 14 appointing Major JE Bryant to oversee conditions of contraband slaves, signed by John P Hawkins, September 16, 1863; Location: Goodrich Landing, Louisiana Format: MDocS (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Rudin # S - 688
  - Confederate Slave Impressment, October 1, 1863; Location: Virginia (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Rudin # S - 42
  - Two black brothers both enlist, October 19, 1863; Location: Fort Smith, Arkansas Format: Ptd Docs (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Rudin # S - 607